<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibleVerses>
  <verse>
    <text>For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.</text>
    <reference>John 3:16</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Trust in the LORD with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 3:5-6</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I can do all things through him who strengthens me.</text>
    <reference>Philippians 4:13</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For I know the plans I have for you, declares the LORD, plans for welfare and not for evil, to give you a future and a hope.</text>
    <reference>Jeremiah 29:11</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD is my shepherd; I shall not want. He makes me lie down in green pastures. He leads me beside still waters. He restores my soul.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 23:1-3</reference>
    <category>Comfort</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But they who wait for the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 40:31</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be strong and courageous. Do not fear or be in dread of them, for it is the LORD your God who goes with you. He will not leave you or forsake you.</text>
    <reference>Deuteronomy 31:6</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 11:28</reference>
    <category>Comfort</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance.</text>
    <reference>2 Peter 3:9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Love is patient and kind; love does not envy or boast; it is not arrogant or rude. It does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice at wrongdoing, but rejoices with the truth.</text>
    <reference>1 Corinthians 13:4-6</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.</text>
    <reference>Romans 8:28</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.</text>
    <reference>Ephesians 2:8-9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come.</text>
    <reference>2 Corinthians 5:17</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.</text>
    <reference>Philippians 4:6-7</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and the knowledge of the Holy One is insight.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 9:10</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.</text>
    <reference>1 John 1:9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be kind to one another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, as God in Christ forgave you.</text>
    <reference>Ephesians 4:32</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers, nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.</text>
    <reference>Romans 8:38-39</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 6:33</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD is my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? The LORD is the stronghold of my life; of whom shall I be afraid?</text>
    <reference>Psalm 27:1</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.</text>
    <reference>Romans 15:13</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But as for me and my house, we will serve the LORD.</text>
    <reference>Joshua 24:15</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.</text>
    <reference>Romans 6:23</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD bless you and keep you; the LORD make his face to shine upon you and be gracious to you; the LORD lift up his countenance upon you and give you peace.</text>
    <reference>Numbers 6:24-26</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 119:105</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Blessed is the man who walks not in the counsel of the wicked, nor stands in the way of sinners, nor sits in the seat of scoffers; but his delight is in the law of the LORD, and on his law he meditates day and night.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 1:1-2</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Rejoice always, pray without ceasing, give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.</text>
    <reference>1 Thessalonians 5:16-18</reference>
    <category>Praise</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The grass withers, the flower fades, but the word of our God will stand forever.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 40:8</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights, with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change.</text>
    <reference>James 1:17</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.</text>
    <reference>Romans 5:8</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made. Wonderful are your works; my soul knows it very well.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 139:14</reference>
    <category>Praise</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 5:16</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 7:7</reference>
    <category>Prayer</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly.</text>
    <reference>John 10:10</reference>
    <category>Life</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I am the vine; you are the branches. Whoever abides in me and I in him, he it is that bears much fruit, for apart from me you can do nothing.</text>
    <reference>John 15:5</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>A soft answer turns away wrath, but a harsh word stirs up anger.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 15:1</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 5:9</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Greater love has no one than this, that someone lay down his life for his friends.</text>
    <reference>John 15:13</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth.</text>
    <reference>1 John 3:18</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For to me to live is Christ, and to die is gain.</text>
    <reference>Philippians 1:21</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth.</text>
    <reference>Colossians 3:2</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.</text>
    <reference>Galatians 5:22-23</reference>
    <category>Spiritual Growth</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>And without faith it is impossible to please him, for whoever would draw near to God must believe that he exists and that he rewards those who seek him.</text>
    <reference>Hebrews 11:6</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be still, and know that I am God. I will be exalted among the nations, I will be exalted in the earth!</text>
    <reference>Psalm 46:10</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness.</text>
    <reference>2 Timothy 3:16</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For we walk by faith, not by sight.</text>
    <reference>2 Corinthians 5:7</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 6:33</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I will instruct you and teach you in the way you should go; I will counsel you with my eye upon you.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 32:8</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous man runs into it and is safe.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 18:10</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Delight yourself in the LORD, and he will give you the desires of your heart.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 37:4</reference>
    <category>Joy</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD will fight for you, and you have only to be silent.</text>
    <reference>Exodus 14:14</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O LORD, make me dwell in safety.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 4:8</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God.</text>
    <reference>Colossians 3:16</reference>
    <category>Praise</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be strong in the Lord and in the strength of his might.</text>
    <reference>Ephesians 6:10</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change.</text>
    <reference>James 1:17</reference>
    <category>Gratitude</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>A friend loves at all times, and a brother is born for adversity.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 17:17</reference>
    <category>Friendship</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful.</text>
    <reference>Hebrews 10:23</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Count it all joy, my brothers, when you meet trials of various kinds, for you know that the testing of your faith produces steadfastness.</text>
    <reference>James 1:2-3</reference>
    <category>Perseverance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The steadfast love of the LORD never ceases; his mercies never come to an end; they are new every morning; great is your faithfulness.</text>
    <reference>Lamentations 3:22-23</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the LORD require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God?</text>
    <reference>Micah 6:8</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>God is our refuge and strength, a very present help in trouble.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 46:1</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Cast your burden on the LORD, and he will sustain you; he will never permit the righteous to be moved.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 55:22</reference>
    <category>Comfort</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 28:20</reference>
    <category>Encouragement</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For I, the LORD your God, hold your right hand; it is I who say to you, "Fear not, I am the one who helps you."</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 41:13</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>He has made everything beautiful in its time. Also, he has put eternity into man's heart, yet so that he cannot find out what God has done from the beginning to the end.</text>
    <reference>Ecclesiastes 3:11</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>And let us not grow weary of doing good, for in due season we will reap, if we do not give up.</text>
    <reference>Galatians 6:9</reference>
    <category>Perseverance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Fear not, for I am with you; be not dismayed, for I am your God; I will strengthen you, I will help you, I will uphold you with my righteous right hand.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 41:10</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But they who wait for the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 40:31</reference>
    <category>Strength</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.</text>
    <reference>Romans 8:28</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me, for I am gentle and lowly in heart, and you will find rest for your souls.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 11:28-29</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The name of the LORD is a strong tower; the righteous man runs into it and is safe.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 18:10</reference>
    <category>Protection</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I have said these things to you, that in me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation. But take heart; I have overcome the world.</text>
    <reference>John 16:33</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But the wisdom from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, open to reason, full of mercy and good fruits, impartial and sincere.</text>
    <reference>James 3:17</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.</text>
    <reference>1 Thessalonians 5:18</reference>
    <category>Gratitude</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law.</text>
    <reference>Galatians 5:22-23</reference>
    <category>Spiritual Growth</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>As a father shows compassion to his children, so the LORD shows compassion to those who fear him.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 103:13</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
</bibleVerses>
