
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibleVerses>
  <verse>
    <text>For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life.</text>
    <reference>John 3:16</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Trust in the LORD with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 3:5-6</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I can do all things through him who strengthens me.</text>
    <reference>Philippians 4:13</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For I know the plans I have for you, declares the LORD, plans for welfare and not for evil, to give you a future and a hope.</text>
    <reference>Jeremiah 29:11</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD is my shepherd; I shall not want. He makes me lie down in green pastures. He leads me beside still waters. He restores my soul.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 23:1-3</reference>
    <category>Comfort</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But they who wait for the LORD shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 40:31</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be strong and courageous. Do not fear or be in dread of them, for it is the LORD your God who goes with you. He will not leave you or forsake you.</text>
    <reference>Deuteronomy 31:6</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 11:28</reference>
    <category>Comfort</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance.</text>
    <reference>2 Peter 3:9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Love is patient and kind; love does not envy or boast; it is not arrogant or rude. It does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice at wrongdoing, but rejoices with the truth.</text>
    <reference>1 Corinthians 13:4-6</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose.</text>
    <reference>Romans 8:28</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, not a result of works, so that no one may boast.</text>
    <reference>Ephesians 2:8-9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come.</text>
    <reference>2 Corinthians 5:17</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.</text>
    <reference>Philippians 4:6-7</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The fear of the LORD is the beginning of wisdom, and the knowledge of the Holy One is insight.</text>
    <reference>Proverbs 9:10</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.</text>
    <reference>1 John 1:9</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Be kind to one another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, as God in Christ forgave you.</text>
    <reference>Ephesians 4:32</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers, nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.</text>
    <reference>Romans 8:38-39</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you.</text>
    <reference>Matthew 6:33</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD is my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? The LORD is the stronghold of my life; of whom shall I be afraid?</text>
    <reference>Psalm 27:1</reference>
    <category>Courage</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope.</text>
    <reference>Romans 15:13</reference>
    <category>Hope</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But as for me and my house, we will serve the LORD.</text>
    <reference>Joshua 24:15</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.</text>
    <reference>Romans 6:23</reference>
    <category>Salvation</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The LORD bless you and keep you; the LORD make his face to shine upon you and be gracious to you; the LORD lift up his countenance upon you and give you peace.</text>
    <reference>Numbers 6:24-26</reference>
    <category>Peace</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Your word is a lamp to my feet and a light to my path.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 119:105</reference>
    <category>Guidance</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Blessed is the man who walks not in the counsel of the wicked, nor stands in the way of sinners, nor sits in the seat of scoffers; but his delight is in the law of the LORD, and on his law he meditates day and night.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 1:1-2</reference>
    <category>Wisdom</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Rejoice always, pray without ceasing, give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you.</text>
    <reference>1 Thessalonians 5:16-18</reference>
    <category>Praise</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>The grass withers, the flower fades, but the word of our God will stand forever.</text>
    <reference>Isaiah 40:8</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights, with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change.</text>
    <reference>James 1:17</reference>
    <category>Faith</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>But God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us.</text>
    <reference>Romans 5:8</reference>
    <category>Love</category>
  </verse>
  <verse>
    <text>I praise you, for I am fearfully and wonderfully made. Wonderful are your works; my soul knows it very well.</text>
    <reference>Psalm 139:14</reference>
    <category>Praise</category>
  </verse>
</bibleVerses>
